good morning welcome to saturday round
tables
or good morning good afternoon good
evening whatever time zone you're in
uh this is where we talk about our
projects explain a bit of what they are
what we've been up to what we're going
to be taking on in the next week and
anything we could use
help with and then if somebody would
like they sit in the hot seat for the
hour
and for the remainder of the hour and we
focus on their project
so who would like to start
i guess i could start
so for reason score i am actually
hiring someone uh to do some
internet research on debates um
i'm going in with a group called the
society library
they are non-profit and they're also
hiring someone to do
research on campaign
something with the election coming up so
we're going to kind of combine forces
have the same research or do
some combined work um outside of that i
haven't been
doing much on the project i am going to
i'm
on vacation for most of next week i'll
be back by friday
for the regular meeting though and uh
i'm i think i've come to the point where
i've decided i need to start making
money again so i have to go back to game
a for a while so
i'm going to start looking for things
that i find interesting
i learn new skills i get to work with
people that are
[Music]
that i can learn from and build
relationships
so those are the feet and then you know
get paid a
living wage not what i was making before
but uh
about half of what i was making before
so
that's the plan we'll see if it happens
that's it for me
all right i guess i can go uh for wiki
election
i've been uh working on the specs for
the next version of the prototype
and as well also been i went out and
grabbed all the data for the congress
and the senate in the u.s
and uh found some of the sort of good
underlying data from
one of the sites that we found when i
was sort of quasi in the hot seat for
where we find data we spent that five or
ten minutes coming up with a bunch of
places to
get data um one of the ones towards the
end had a really good
uh list was actually on github and it is
like
a list of all of the the current
uh congress people and senators and all
the former ones and
the various things to do with
legislation so that'll be
quite useful going forward so i've been
prepping that so that when uh
matusha's done the legislation part of
the the prototype we'll have some data
to throw in there
and that we might be able to see some
quasi-interesting information soon in
the prototype granted not anything
unique
but uh at least it'll be there and we
can build on it so
that's it for me
okay um well i've got three
three things that i'm working on which
are all in a kind of state of flux at
the moment
and um in terms of definitions haven't
really got any
um for them just yet so i'm just gonna
let stuff image
um but yeah so that's that's all i've
got to say at the moment
all right i can go well my douche gets
set up uh
so my project is solution racing we pick
a new
topic every week and talk for an hour
and come up with a solution
and this last week we tackled shelter
and came up with an amazing solution
that made me really want to focus on
these specific
four solution raisings of shelter
the community of the meta community
education and food
because with that you can free 10 000
people from game and they can
concentrate on game b
um this last week also i was a guest on
a
on a podcast that is future thinkers
adjacent
called upgrading society that has a very
cool
premise of they kind of are doing what
we're doing they they have someone in
the
in who they they interview and they
score them based on
three the clarity the action
and the potential and then they're going
to be following them through
and um so meeting with them several
times and figuring out how to kind of
connect them with with each other
and they have future thinkers audience
from what i understand so they're
they're starting with more of a
foundation of viewers and isn't out yet
but i'm excited i mentioned of course
our sense making and together tech and
game b
was game b was what we were focused on
but i also mentioned solution raising so
some of them will be coming to to that
hopefully on wednesday and continuing
forward
and then after this today uh carrie
yvette and i are meeting for
culture of wii starting with three which
i am super
excited about um just see what comes out
of that
and including next week when we're
focused on solution raising itself and
kind of
what we do to move forward so
that is what and uh so because of those
four what i could use help with from
someone
is a spreadsheet that
is able to be used to calculate the
shelter
piece that we talked about this last
week so i tried to do it myself and
it nearly broke my brain yesterday i
kind of could almost do it but i i need
someone who can do excel spreadsheets i
kind of can do the basic math but
not that how many months does it take
for everyone to get housed and how much
rent and that kind of thing so that is
what i can use help with
and matush you want to give your update
uh so first i did some uh
more conceptual than actual coding work
on weekly lectures
reception and uh there is something i
would
uh like to talk about uh about scoring
and about matrix uh
later hopefully um because it's
the picture that appears uh and it
starts to emerging as
uh is interesting so we need to talk
about it uh
second my own personal project is
hyperlogos which is the visualization uh
and there's a lot of hats as they say um
did some work on that as well um did
some
um participated in a meeting about uh
mind mapping uh in uh open global mind
and yeah it's going slowly but
surely in the right direction
all right now what do we focus on for
the next hour or the remainder of the
hour
because no one really has anything hot
seat my need for a spreadsheet is not
going to be
in the hot seat because i i have
something for you
um like because because i said i've been
working on stuff on the back end and
content types what what specific right
i'm just going to ask you as a general
just you know in terms of
content types for stuff that you are
doing
that you know obviously this is what
we're doing um
uh i'd like to ask you is there anything
like you know you've got a page article
event groups what have you um specific
to what you're doing is there anything
that you can think of
um that you might like so say like
facebook the group
right what do you think that's that's
missing
that you would like to actually have a
content type for
in terms of categorizing and organizing
stuff
i think i've not explained that very
well
so do you mean things like i mean for us
video is a pretty obvious one that we're
all going to need
um standalone images possibly if you
just want
to throw up an infographic like some
kind of a write-up where it's probably a
combination of text and images
do you mean stuff like that yeah and in
terms of sort of writing about your
project
and information that you want out there
about your project that you'd like you
know to be able to sort out right we're
doing this
um because i know there's sort of like
articles and discussions
and stuff like that as well um
so things like that really because as i
said because of drupal and that and i've
been going through all the fields and
the entity references and
and how you can actually create a view
of stuff
with all these you know all the all the
the different types of contents
and also the taxonomy teams and
um terms and i'll forget the name for
that now
you know what i mean um like you can
have
you know all the content that a project
might post it
sort of its purpose let me
try and clarify that so and carrie
corrected me if i'm wrong but so in
content management systems you generally
have content types
so in our case i imagine kerry did you
already build one for a project
well i'm in the process of just sort of
going through all the different types of
fields and what you can have for now you
can relate it and
how you can gather content different
bits of content together
for for an example if you had a content
type for project you'd have project name
who the owner is and stuff like that
yeah and then then you have a content
type of blog art girl content type of
page con
so it's any type of group of fields of
data
that yeah that okay as a group yeah
right
like as i said i'm shit at explaining
things like so
it's not an easy concept and especially
for me
who doesn't like labels and anything
yeah and content types are really bad
phrase because everyone thinks oh well
yeah video image and it's like yeah
that's
not what they were like in the category
so is it
kind of like different tables then yeah
it is okay yeah
yeah so i'm just thinking it exactly is
stored as one's a table in most
right so so basically like
us in terms of your projects and stuff
um is there any specific content types
that you might like to have um that i
haven't thought about
yet i think that's mostly what i'm
trying to ask
in a in a kind of case
well yeah yeah i'm just doing um
something i'm just going through a
couple of tutorials on
how to to put all the terms together and
the taxonomy terms and the
you know um because you can have tags
and you can have taxonomies and as i
said you can basically field everything
you know we stick everything into its
own field
with whatever type of thing that you you
might like
you know i mean so and because um
i'm just i suppose with with projects
and stuff
um what would be kind of relevant to you
and yours
basically because if i can kind of get a
grasp on that
then make something that that's relevant
like some events
definitely for the the videos and stuff
videos images
uh groups user groups so to together
tech would be
and also would would actually together
tech be an actual
a project itself by the way
i i think so right okay so yeah
i thought we would have envisioned it
yeah okay then well that that's a that's
a start
so in terms in terms of
like i said i've already got that the
help wanted and the help needed
and who's involved um all the links to
whatever they're doing
and and stuff like that but is there
anything else that
that you might like or might might want
i can't think of anything else right
yeah i mean once we see the basics some
some ideas might pop up
yeah exactly i think as we actually
start to try to like add
some content things will probably pop up
but it sounds like you've sort of got
the
the basics cover to start with which we
can probably make do with yeah so as i
said
i'll get the basics up in that and then
come in and tell me
um what you like what you don't like
what you don't want
um and then after that we can talk about
the back end
of stuff as well um but like as i said
i'm just trying to get the
the stuff that you can actually just see
without having to join
and stuff like that and and because of
the way drupal's organized you can
actually do
inline editing so you don't have to
you know you can just do it you don't
have to go and find the menu you can
actually do it from the actual piece of
content that you've done
as well so so yeah so i suppose that was
um
i was trying to get me address all of
that and thinking what people wanted
um but yeah
okay yeah i think as billy said sort of
the sooner that we can see
even just like the you know even if you
feel that it's only 60
done as long as we can sort of see a
project and see stuff that project is
doing
i think that will help start putting
some context around like
okay i can see how it's being structured
and okay i want these extra
uh content types there and so on
like one of the things i'm not sure if
you have it do you have a spot to
attract people yet
melissa do you have a spot to track
people as separate from projects right
so like yeah yeah
you can actually do everything on um
users
so i ate that word useless okay you know
what i mean
you can show that to the public though i
know some things are really iffy about
showing user information to the public
oh well you could just have like this is
why i was thinking about the user groups
so so like you know um together tech
is is maybe sponsoring this event
you know what i mean for hosting the the
conversations and that like
jubilees solution raisins will just have
i don't know whether
jubilee you wanted just a kind of
solution raisins group
user group so then anyone who's come
into kind of solution reasons can
see it's part of a bigger group you know
i mean um
so maybe have that so be sponsored by so
each of the events whoever's hosting it
it's kind of like
i don't know whether you want me to use
the word sponsor or just hosting
hosting the event or or whatever because
if we get
down the line sometime in the future
where people
you know are actually you know giving us
money for things
which should be like that was true which
is nice
um that you know um we can maybe like
or maybe want to come and sponsor um a
conversation or something like that
um you could have them separate if you
wanted i'm just trying to think far off
into the
the future right uh sorry separate from
i was confused what you're yes i want to
thank for solution raising yeah yeah
yeah
yeah no no it's just like like the user
group for solution reasons right
but um because there's you know events
that are sponsored
by somebody or because obviously
you could have it may be sponsored by a
user group or somebody else might be
hosting it
so would you so to have the host hosting
would you would it be a
a hosting group or a oh god
well are user groups effectively
projects then
um you could set them up as a type of
content that they are
you know what i mean and then that could
be i'm talking for us not for like
the specific terms that drupal might use
like
if i were to go and navigate this site
as just a user especially
somebody who's viewing it as the public
and i view a list
of projects and i click on a project am
i viewing
a user group at that point or am i doing
something completely separate called you
know a project
yeah yeah you you're seeing the the
actual project
itself but it'll be kind of hosted by
or sponsored by um and then you'll just
what when you click on that that'll take
you to a page
of who that group is and what what
they're all about
you know what i mean so they can get
more information about so like you know
so say like
if it was sponsored by together tech
right they click on together tech
that and there'd be a piece of content
which we're basically a page saying that
we're together tech bloody bloody blah
there's links here's what is who we are
you know i mean so that would go to that
and where to contact you
as well but that would be part of the
project thingy and all
you know does that make that about as
clear as mud
so i think your concern about
data privacy is usually there is a kind
of a public and a private side of the
user data
so as long as you make it you just have
to make sure you make it clear which
pieces are public
or private although yeah i think most
people filling stuff in here they'll
expect everything to be public
except for their email address hopefully
true yeah i guess i'm
also wondering like if we start to get
you know
workers and like people that want to
chip in on projects but
maybe not be like the public face of
anything
they might not want their profile shown
at all whereas
i guess i'm kind of talking about like
almost public
personalities as a part of the projects
right like so
for example if if i could look at reason
score
somewhere on there probably see oh okay
bentley is kind of the main slash only
person's
currently on that site who's a part of
reason score then if i go
to together tech i'll see a list of
people and one of them is that same
bentley person
[Music]
yeah yes okay you're gonna have a way of
associating people with projects
yeah yeah so like because obviously um
like for the anonymous user they'll just
see the project
and who's there but if you won't see any
of the
the you know any details from what we've
got in the back end
or any conversations unless you want to
make them public they'll only see that
but any information that you want out in
the public you can see that but i
wouldn't i wouldn't be like you know
and if you wanted to to show people
where your links are to you
your personal profiles on on various
sites there'll be stuff for that
right but it wouldn't be any kind of
in-depth you'd have to join
to actually become part of um because i
see it as
just a container ship at the moment and
i'm a pirate
captain fighter so carrie when you say
back in you're meaning the
the private area as opposed to yeah yeah
because i've just seen it as a kitchen
table now
they yeah yeah the only it's a kitchen
table
when you're when you're talking
technology the back end off it
also it specifically means the server as
opposed to
it's okay so we might find a different
term for that just so it won't confuse i
don't want to confuse the techies
it might confuse adrial too because he
he he works at that and that weird
non-techie techie or i guess non-dev
techie i'm not sure how to
distract myself yeah there you go well
as i said i'll just refer to it as the
kitchen table then
because um basically it's just for
people to gather around the kitchen
table really
um and make something and develop
something out of that
so that's i'll use the kitchen table and
that would be the private part right
yeah yeah the kitchen table
[Laughter]
the first special dining page would say
welcome to the reception
of the site and then
you must speak pirate to get it
i think we should all be pirates because
i was looking at him
there you know the pirate party that set
up and how they set up and that and i
thought oh
swarms and pirates and things and then i
was thinking about making stuff
so i'll make it all kind of pirate tops
to it
i was having i think it's i was too hot
the other day
i don't do sunshine quite well so um so
yeah
so it's just to be a bit loopy
so jubilee i'll take a look at the video
and see if it's a
easy fit to get a spreadsheet out
because i'm pretty good with that oh i
don't know if
watching the video would be an easy i
just
we had talked about a habitat for
humanity like structure
where ten thousand people per union ten
dollars a month and
that would in my mouth equal about three
tiny homes per month
if they're around you know three thirty
thousand to make
and then once you're living in one
you're paying rent back to the pool
so every to every like there's three
different changing it's
it's how much does it cost to make one
tiny house it could be twenty thousand
could be fifty thousand i have no idea
how much rent you're getting and then
how much membership fee is because it
grows exponentially right we're starting
with three per month but as rent
increases
holding membership the same how how soon
can we get those 10 000 people in houses
by my calculation it was like
300 years i was like okay that's not
quite so sustainable
um yeah so just wanting to be able to
play with those three numbers
and i was doing it very like okay this
month and then we add it
and it goes like it's yeah my excel
capability isn't enough to notice my
math it turns out
i know my math was better but
yeah that makes sense trying to figure i
if i'm trying to decide if i have enough
information to try and do a simulation
i think i do i'll i'll hit you up on
message or if i
can't if i'm missing something awesome
i'm also good i'm gonna ask my mom
because she
somewhat knows spreadsheets and i don't
know if she can actually do this
but i'm gonna ask so you know
she's a parent she's not there yeah i'd
appreciate that
if you've got a version that you've
already started it might help to send
that to bentley and to mom as well
just because i i find that seeing what
somebody started on even if it's
terrible
seeing what seeing what you've labeled
things and seeing what you've tried
at least for me sometimes it doesn't
have to be like oh okay i see what
they're trying to do here
i don't know yeah because i was like
doing it by month of life and then we
over the next month then i was also like
trying to have this time lag of three
months how
long it would take to make one so you're
not paying rent until at that point but
honestly if you're
yeah maybe you are paying rent for the
three months for building it because
it's like a down payment i don't know
building normal standards houses
tiny houses tiny oh okay yeah
no you wouldn't be able to build a
standard house for 30 000 but being able
like how much material is in there the
idea is also it's a
like a barn raising like habitat for
humanity you're putting in sweat
equities there's no labor involved
or very little labor involved you might
have to get the experts but we're all
putting in
time so it's only the resources and we
can bulk by them and
that's also as you continue on if you're
building three you can't both buy
when you're building 15 20 per month you
can
more we'll buy it i also wonder at what
point we could start
looking at the 3d printed houses i'm not
sure if those are
all scalable yet or what but that's been
around for a while now and those seem
pretty cool yeah part of the tiny house
model in my head anyway is that they're
movable
so it means that as you're figuring out
how to build a community you can move
them around to see what the
configuration is if i don't like this
community i can move it to somewhere
else that you that
part of shelter is land resources and
labor
and so land can can change sorry to
build a house right like to get a
physical structure you need a land to
put it on you need the labor
and you need the resources we're sharing
in the labor we're hopefully both buying
the resources then we don't know where
the land like maybe i own lands and i'm
putting a tiny house on there
or we're figuring out an infrastructure
to deal with farmers and there's gonna
be five
here like that the tiny houses can move
so that
they're not because the other thing is
then yeah cobb houses are actually
cheaper to build but then they're
physically
there and you legally can't do that in
some places
and so like working with the flow of
community
you can own a tiny house and move it
about and or
we if if like i'm just gonna use
together tech owns the tiny houses
then we can then if one person isn't
using it we can decide where they move
to
right but there's there's more focus
yeah so at least the first wave will be
mobile tiny homes and then
after there you can say because you
might end up with almost like a fleet of
mobile ones that can move around and
that may even end up being your crew
that's building the other homes
and then they sort of move around and
leave permanent
homes as they go yeah if they
if they can't right there'd be multiple
kinds but yeah that was kind of what
how to build their own houses and then
we had a fractal of uh
there was at least one culture in the
history of the world that
were pretty good at moving houses around
and they lived in
like the uh cards
the big cards and they were bans
the caravans for the dancing singing and
labor
yes yeah i think the natives were quite
good at
doing like sort of mobile homes where
they would have certain
i guess types of settlements that could
easily be moved you know because you can
go to
an area of the prairies head up to your
thing either the
the weather changes or the herds move
you pick up you move
yeah the central native americans
yeah oh yeah i guess you should probably
say native americans because native
americans
yeah and then uh the mongols back in
around
in ancient times generally
yeah uh so and you were saying
rent so does that mean it goes in
perpetuity it's not you end up owning
the house
it's not a mortgage yeah the idea is if
we're getting together as 10 000 people
and wanting to house 10 000 people that
you unders like
you're paying what i was saying is i
started 500 it wasn't enough 750
a month but the idea is if we're
releasing people from game
a to concentrate on game b that 750
isn't necessarily paid by the person it
might be paid by the community
right like we needed we need an income
that pays for 10 people because we have
10 people that need to live here
you know like like it doesn't mean
necessarily that i'm paying that rent
but the rent needs to be paid for that
structure so that there's more houses
being built later
so it's like membership fees and that is
how it exponentially goes otherwise
we're only going to have three per month
right whatever the beginning is it kind
of just stays that every time
yeah and i think if that's being done
like under the umbrella of an
organization that will end up doing
other things that that can sort of end
like
i think it totally makes sense for the
organization to still own it because
it's the
you know the group the co-op whatever
you want to call it that built it
and if you charge rent and the person
never owns it but the rent is reasonable
then that's already a win over the
current system
and you know it's sort of meant to be
people that maybe normal landlords
wouldn't want to
to rent to or that just wouldn't because
the person couldn't afford it
i think that still ends up being omni
one maybe not quite to the extent that
the person would want
but it you know could help them get on
their feet and then
you could give them options though that
um if they wanted to sort of like buy
the house
wanted to stay you know what i mean and
you know
wanted to sort of like own somewhere
you know i mean so you could give them
the option to do that as well
you know if you paid this for rent
you're just renting if you paid this
for rent that extra amount goes towards
buying it and after a certain amount of
time you'll own it
i i guess i'm still a bit confused
because jubilee is saying the person in
the house may not be the person paying
the rent
right yeah that part confused me like my
understanding from what you
said is that you would get yours your
subscribers to
you know this housing system they would
be paying into a system that would
constantly just be focusing on building
new homes
and then you also have people who are
paying rent paying to that same system
you know so
the first year maybe you're building
three months and then the next year
because you've got
people paying rent you might be able to
afford to build four a month
and then the the following year five six
and then you know eight and then ten
and and so on i would assume that the
rent just goes into there and if you're
having other people pay for it
you might just have like separate
projects where like hey if you're
also wanting to chime in and help people
parent in this village in california
there's a separate one for that that
people pay into
is that i just meant like the rent is
paid for the shelter right so we're
saying that if you
if you have this shelter there's 750
per month it could be me who pays it
writing come out of my disability amount
and come out of my
my um you know contract work and
combined with or
it could be hey these 10 people are
living together they're focused on
creating this technology
so the technology companies paying their
rent right that like
it's part of having an intentional
community is having an income that pays
for
whatever it is we set up right so it's
not because how do you make money if you
don't have a job right if you don't have
an income so it's like right part of it
is coming and
trading in a way that that is omni-win
right that is like oh we're releasing
from game a
so that we can focus on releasing other
people from game a
um maybe i can pay rent maybe i can't
right it's on like a per
person basis in which case it is the
together tech that owns it and if you
want to own it outright
then they're you know maybe one in ten
is is sold that way
sold for profit so that more of it can
go back into the system but the idea is
we're just figuring out how can we
how do i get a roof over my head that is
yes i want it to be permanent right i
don't want to be kicked out because i
can't pay the rent but we got to figure
that out because
we need more money coming into the pool
so that it can go to the next person and
the next person the next person
yeah i think membership fees are not
paying the rent that was the part i
wanted
no membership fees are the um ten
dollars per month to actually be part
of because because with ten dollars a
month times the ten thousand then you
can make
my rough calculations three per month so
that is the
so once you start paying rent you're no
longer paying that ten dollars a month
you're not paying your rent right
but in the beginning it's like right the
idea is is you're
helping house people right that
including you possibly
but maybe not right that was part of the
conversation that we have it's like
maybe it is more like habitat for
humanity
where the 10 000 are focusing on
housing a thousand of us not ten
thousand of us but yeah that the rent
doesn't come from the membership fee the
membership fee is just a way to get
money pooled so that we can buy
and create so buy resources to create
tiny houses with
that also it exponentially grows because
of
the membership and the rent that is
going to
that makes sense yeah i think that that
makes sense
and it doesn't need to be 10 a month
that was the other thing is i was like
maybe it's 25
a month maybe it's because the more it
is the more houses we can build of
course
but it also depends on what people want
to put in right like i'd be willing to
put in 10
a month even if i never got a house i
don't know if i'd be willing to put in
a month probably but that's probably
about my cut off
yeah and then the the interesting part
is is there any sort of um
i think like subscription tier almost
where it's like is there a reason for
the person to pay more or is it just
to pay more well the idea wouldn't be it
would be like we would set it at 10 or
we would set it to 25 right i see so
there's just
a single in yeah on the spreadsheet
anyway right not hey we have this many
people at 10 and there's many people at
25.
that's also part of
and in case of like bigger settlements
uh
it would make also sense to um
connect the rent and paying for staff
uh to uh perhaps services that the
person
owning or renting the house uh we need
an awards for it
uh could provide to the community if
it's
like for example there is a community
having an open slot for a
dentist and if someone happens to
uh want to leave game a and everything
and just move to a
smaller place where uh for just
providing the service that the person
already does provide
in exchange for money uh here would be
in exchange for
uh like accommodation and everything
that the community provides
so that's an idea
yeah the idea at least like this is a
brand new i was two days ago i was like
oh my god these four solution racing
solved everything like i'm like if we
can figure out education because i need
my kids to be educated
and with copenhagen it's like that's not
safe how do we educate children
food and shelter and community so you
can move around and have
and if we focus on the autonomous
individual right that it isn't about
everyone has to be omni-win every second
of every day it's like hey do you have
shelter do you have food how do we have
a community how do we work through it
then there's no one in power over you
once you figure out shelter
food and community and then you freed
yourself from game and you can start
concentrating more on game b
and so in my ideal world the people who
first get shelter the people who are
most powerful in game b
right the people who are most able to
contribute to game b
um without because they're
sheltered and then they can they that's
a whole other exponential growth right
that has nothing to do with currency oh
well i'm sure it's something to the
currency
but it's if if
like the five of us were sheltered right
like we're creating together tech we're
figuring we're figuring that out
we're going to be able to concentrate on
creating those omni-win solutions the
scheduling app and those kind of things
and whoever those people are
it's not necessarily sheltering the
people who are the most in need of it
it's need slash um
contribution to the community because
there's going to be more impact from
that
i think because you're starting out
focusing on the mobile tiny homes
you could sort of like the part that
we've talked about with people
getting homes and training services for
it i wonder if your first group are the
people that are building the
the mobile tiny homes if they set up
some sort of like even a possibly
permanent community let's just say
somewhere in the u.s
they get the free housing and then a
part of that is they churn out these
mobile tiny homes which hopefully
lowers the cost of it um and then you
can ship them out from there and say
like oh okay we'll
we'll we'll figure that from the from
this point we can ship out the mobile
tiny homes you know in a 100 mile radius
and then you can plant those spots and
have your sort of mobile communities and
and they can move around and then you
know later on you set up another
permanent one maybe on the opposite
coast
yeah there's a reason it's the fort one
of the the four solution reasons is the
meta community is the hundred groups of
100 figuring out those
solutions for meta community of like hey
how do we do plumbing and how do we do
this how do we how do we
do that and a bigger infrastructure of
where do you want your tiny house to be
right like which community do you want
to live in are they okay with you being
there and what is that work you're doing
that is contributing to
to game b around it and
yeah yeah that was part of the solution
raising was hey why don't we house the
people building it first
and they can tr they could even travel
around right like they could be a
community that travels around and builds
them
because they're a fam like out of family
a grouping of 10 families
that although they're maybe they're
nomadic right they're like yeah this is
our ideal we get us to have
a connection in community but we get to
travel around or they have a permanent
structure and they ship them out
or i mean any number of things right
it's like what works for
them as an individual and what works for
the for the bigger
bigger people to get more houses that
end up being very cool
like having this this nomadic tribe of
settlement builders but like in
in the modern day yeah and tech i mean
tech
it's like the builders and the tech
people right that are like hey
building i mean i want that i want to
the other options like buy a hotel and
just start a tech company
which is also a an option but
figuring out together how do we house
ourselves how do we keep
growing that
kind of being a snail that you i just
imagine the
like tiny house that i can just take
with me everywhere i go
and then i will be able to uh pick the
best location that
feels just right at the moment be it at
the sea or in the mountains or whatever
that would make sense and then the
settlement would not be a
set of houses and renting and everything
it would be more like the space for
camping
where you can just get your house into
the
spot into the place and then it could
connect to
like uh power water and everything
that's necessary uh
and then you could leave there for as
long as you want or
as long as the community lets you stay
in case you are not the
best number of communities but yeah
that would make sense i think it's a
sorry constituent
it's a there is something to like being
able to move
along with like everything like if my
house had legs
and i could tell it to just slowly move
somewhere else
that'd be nice and that is like
i don't want to be nomadic i want to be
in one location
and develop roots and do that but i
would love for other people to be able
to
to come through that community and i
would love for or if i was nomadic i
would like to have
five or six families especially one with
a kid around my kids age
that we were traveling together so we
have we still have that connection those
roots
and you still need to grow food and you
still need to do those things which
require
more of a like a subtle location but yes
as an individual
if you want to you can travel around and
see this bigger connection
and as long as the community is willing
and you're needed that can go and then
there can also be ones that are more
permanent
and you know there's maybe two nomadic
people throughout it and there's just a
lot of
um what is resilience right that there's
a lot of options that can happen and
it's about the individual and the group
of like what works for you
what calls to you where do you want to
be if you want to be in the mountains
one week and then the ocean the next
awesome and you have this bigger meta
community that you can go
like you're not just going to parking at
the ocean you know this there's this
ocean community in this this forest one
and
you've probably connected with them on
video chats in the meta community and
all this other stuff so
all over the world right i can go in to
new zealand and know that there's gonna
be one i probably won't move my tiny
hose
i will have to trade right or something
like that but
and i saw so sorry for laughing i was
just at this picture of this house like
a
house with legs well done just like made
me laugh
the house with legs remind me of baba
yaga you know
i wanted one of their houses yeah
it's slightly different an idea um
did you see the mortal engines i think
the title was
and it was about it's kind of science
fiction
about the future in which cities are
movable and it's
like you have the biggest round was
london at the moment
i think so it was a whole city on very
very huge giant um
what's the the trucks i think of the
something you have on the tank and
that's it was able to move like whole
thing
and i just imagine because there can be
tiny houses in forms of
just trailers that people use especially
in us
i guess and yeah and
then i also remember seeing uh some
projects about
uh not so tiny uh places like
you would have everything could be
packed on a
uh on a trailer but then it could expand
when you arrive
at the place you want to be and then uh
you have like
not very small house it was like normal
size almost
so there's something something to that
that as well
yeah i mean i actually realized
so it's like that you know this big
caravan of like a giant sort of
moving center part and all these tiny
homes and you know just people's
vehicles all in a caravan but you know
instead of dystopian like the burning
man
and all the vehicles there just
art right yeah cool
very uh very big advantage over
what we have now and what we have now is
houses that are just functional but
they are not um or not always at least
piece of art
you know what uh when i think about
solar pump what comes to mind is uh
like places of the villages that in
which
um every house house is slightly
different
and every house and every building is uh
not only just uh a place performing
a function but also uh something that
was created to be both functional and
beautiful and
yeah and state of art something
like it would provide a very
uh very good environment much better
than
uh like having rows of
same size same look houses that we have
now in so many places
okay here you do but you're not muted
now you're software muted
hey technology okay now i can hear you
all right
oh and now i don't remember i was going
to say
but hey second viewer
all right so i'm wondering how this ties
into something that i've been
like sort of trying to figure out how it
fits into together tech in this whole
thing
which is like i've got a fair number of
game a ideas
and i'm wondering or like not even game
a
profitable enterprise ideas which could
very easily fit into a game b
enterprise and possibly help fund tech
you know
tech projects and housing and stuff like
that so i guess i'm wondering how
aid those two fit together just at the
most basic level
um and then how to start
this sort of profitable company piece
but under like a co-op
umbrella where you know eventually you
would end up where the people working on
it would be
getting a salary but then all the
profits of that company
would just be going into this game b
ecosystem to help you know pay for
reasons go around wikileaks
and housing and that's one of the
reasons i know we have we share this
vision somewhat of like instead of
having an intentional community that's
that's source of income is food based
right hey we're gonna make our own jams
we're gonna make our own honey
which is we're feeding ourselves and
feeding maybe we have that connection
maybe that is how some of them
make an income but technology is
powerful like profitable and if we can
use it to create kb
why not so yeah if we can create ones
that it's fully transparent where the
money is and where it's coming from
where it's going
but it's also yes paying people a living
wage and
creating something that is profitable
and there's a ton of technology that
you've had
ideas that could be profitable
yeah what i have in mind is it's like an
omni-wind blackstone where it's like
this giant company that owns tech that
owns
you know farms that owns real estate
owns all the stuff
where the tech is meant to make money
and the real estate is meant to grow and
also make money
but it's not paying out shareholders
it's going back into the company to help
you know buy more tech companies and
help start more tech companies and do
more
more real estate so it can grow even
more i think
fingers and lots of pies adriel fingers
in lots of pies
different types of pies as well you know
what i mean yeah exactly
diversified it's a good idea in gaming
it's a good idea in game b
so um and then i guess on that note i'm
wondering if either bentley or matush
either a no salesforce or b wants to
learn it
because i've got a couple of projects
that i'd like to do soon
and uh i know you know the
my part of salesforce quite well i just
i'm not a
a developer if push comes to shove i
might learn it for this because that i
think is a pretty
you know narrow way to learn it but i
think it would also
be cool to start a project with like me
a developer and
you know somebody of a more like
marketing role
to get that launched because you don't
need that much to do
an app in that ecosystem it's funny
because you mentioned salesforce because
um
i just downloaded the career guide to
salesforce because i was looking for
something
and i fell across it and i was like oh
what's this so i just
i just downloaded it to see what it was
all about and that so um
so i'd be interested yeah i mean it's a
like potentially a very profitable
industry there are like
very large companies that only offer
things on top of the salesforce
ecosystem
that's my day job because i'm a
salesforce admin
but so you
you have some plugin ideas for sales
some sales for
app ideas as as they call them but yeah
essentially a plug-in where it's like
one is a really easy win like i have to
go do a bit more research
but it's uh an industry where there's
like
you know i i think the company i
like i want to say 50 grand a year
on this tool that i think you could
build
a simple layer in salesforce and maybe
charge 10 grand a year
and all of a sudden you've got this
thing that is saving companies money and
now you've got this 10 grand a year
going into a you know a software company
you know if you have 10 of those you're
at the the
100 000 dollar mark and that's in my
mind a lot
easier bridge to gap with like you know
companies that you can directly market
to
they've got sort of their store with the
app exchange for salesforce all that
type of thing i want to turn this into a
sales pitch for salesforce but yeah
i've uh i've one of the options for me
making money is to make
some um small to medium-sized
plug-ins and different um that's usually
a good way to start rather than building
a product completely from scratch
you're building on someone else's thing
but it's usually a
a temporary thing or you know you can't
rely on it fully but it's a great place
to start
um so yeah so it so maybe we should
schedule some time and see if um
see if i agree on the market because it
would take an investment of time right
right yeah yeah and that's i guess a
part of the long-term conversation for
this it's a project like this
what does that look like for the people
who start it versus you know
after it's actually a company operating
paying people a salary
that one's obvious it would operate
fairly like game a just you know
as omni when is possible but the
founders and sort of the initial startup
crew there would be special
accommodations because you can't really
pay them until
it's launched yeah yeah and and if
you're
founding a company like that then you
know that you're not going to become
bill gates or elon musk because right
yes
exactly the the founders like it end up
being you know
probably in the company overall i would
think which i think is how mondragon
works i've heard
where there's like a capped multiplier
where like the highest paid person can
only make you know
x times what the lowest paid person is
and you don't get equity in the company
either right
exactly all the equity goes back into
the company to help it grow so like yeah
you are going to end up as jeff bezos or
elon musk like you won't become a
billionaire
but you could end up you know being like
you know on the board of a billion
dollar company
you just wouldn't have direct access to
that money in the same way that
a game a player would which yeah it
turns out they don't have that much of a
direct access exactly it's not actually
that
it's all on paper but liquid for them
anyway yeah
but at some point a lot of it is yeah so
yeah that would
um that'd be interesting i hadn't
combined my game a designs with my game
b aspirations yet to think about the
impact of building something really cool
watching it make a billion dollars
and then making the same salary i'm
making now
i do think haven't quite at least for
the start there does need to be some
sort of like a
not even comparable in numbers wise at
all but some sort of like a hey
if you're a part of that founding crew
where if you were to because i could
keep this idea and just game a
incorporate as a for-profit company and
potentially make
a bunch of money right or i could join
up with you and we could do that in a
gaming company
so yeah there is that part of what's the
draw to bring this to
the yeah an incentive for the investment
and the risk-taking but not an unlimited
upside which yeah it's silly people are
saying like well if you don't have an
unlimited upside
who would start these businesses and i'm
like do you really think if bill gates
got a couple billion less than he has
now today he wouldn't have started
marketing if he got one
you don't think that's good i've only
got how is he worth
80 billion it's likely he only has 5
billion now
oh well then just throw it all out yeah
i would i would never started the
company
if i knew that limit was there i don't
think so anyways
yeah that's that's the like to say that
there isn't a risk to start a company
there of course is and so if if you're
taking on the risk there should be some
kind of incentive i mean we're taking on
a risk
but we're also choosing like it's like
right i choose to spend this hour taking
on like
yeah on my deathbed why did i waste that
hour it's not no that's not gonna happen
i'm gonna be happy that i was here but
there's like if we're putting in tens of
thousands of dollars
yeah you know what i'm gonna need a
financial compensation that is
equivalent later on and
to be in that tension but know that
you're never gonna make a billion
dollars because tech is risky
and yet it's powerful and if we do it
together it's less risky and more
powerful but there's a
ton of potential for profit and if we
can
be in that and be like where is that
profit going so that it can create more
game b
i'd upside all the way in my mind so
markush is that something you're
interested in as well
yeah i'll definitely take a look at it
and uh yes it sounds
sounds good and besides what i wanted to
add to this is
uh we as humans all we have is as i
recently
heard someone said uh what we have is
time
energy and agency this is all we got and
there is nothing else
the money and profits and power and
everything
these are illusions so i need to stop
right now
but yes the game be for me starts with
freeing up
my time my energy and my agency from
external forces and when i do that
i'll be happy like that
and so i guess there's at least the two
different parts there's the actually
talking about the project
but then there is the kind of trying to
build a system around
what would it take for somebody like me
or bentley or somebody who like
has skills that are in demand in game a
and could make a you know a game a
salary and
if you started a company be quite you
know
off what are the advantages and i think
one of the advantages once the company
is established
is you take away the initial risk part
where you say yeah in game a if you were
to invest and you know
to get a loan and invest your money
that's obviously you taking a risk where
yeah in gay may you that you should have
some sort of payoff or you wouldn't do
that
which kind of goes back to it it would
be interesting if it was kind of a
universal basic income
thing that you're going to make this
salary and you now at some point
maybe you don't have to work or don't
have to work for the next year and then
you can focus your time on other game b
projects and other people take over
right or you can find someone else or
something that would be an interesting
thing because that's
that's one of the things that that makes
it rough about
not having such a big the reason i was
able to take
all this time and work on game b
projects is because i
you know made some extra you know i'm
not working i haven't worked for six
months
um but that's going to come to an end um
so it'd be interesting yeah yeah if we
could so it'd be interesting to sit down
and figure out how to calculate what
that
that risk and that what the upside is
and what the limits are
yeah and i think with this particular
thing one of the advantages
is that risk to start a company is
incredibly low
because you're working on somebody
else's infrastructure all you have to do
is
learn that ecosystem which you know if
you plan to do
other projects going forward is then
wasted time and the only potentially
waste of time is actually doing the
project
yeah it doesn't have as high of an
upside because you're on someone else's
line
and they can kick you off at any time
well yeah salesforce is pretty
solid there but and actually a couple of
the projects
that have mined there's a good chance
that they would end up buying
which then has a a different
conversation on what happens if somebody
acquires a game b project can they
and if they can then you know what's the
game b payout
versus what goes back into this company
to help fund the other stuff
yeah so it'd be interesting to work out
all those a model kind of agreement and
that makes me think maybe
protocol of is that one of them there's
a couple places where they're working on
kind of the agreements of organizations
that are in this space of
not profit of not unlimited profit
so it'd be looking good to see what's
already out there and stuff
yeah ourselves
right this was a fruitful hour i'm going
to
uh duck out pretty soon so we can meet
uh
meet our third person in our culture of
we starting with three
pretty soon and get some stuff going for
that
uh
i see
oh never mind then i just saw the
private chat was that
that's gonna be never mind if i would
read things we'd be fine
all right we can still hang out for
another few minutes uh
i really i mean my vision in the
beginning when i first came into game b
was a netflix of apps right so people
were paying 10 bucks a month to get
access to a catalog of apps
and the issue is we don't have any apps
so why would anyone put 10 a month in
that being said if you had ten thousand
people putting ten dollars a month in so
we could go
and buy apps so you could say hey what's
the most useful one
um my guess is there's tons of companies
that would rather be bought by anyone
but google
and they have that effect like they can
see how much competition there is that
they're probably gonna
gonna die away and if we just want them
for 10 000 people right the
the team building ones and all of these
these different ones then
i think there would be a be a profitable
game
yeah i wonder if we were around
and had that money when good what was
the good thing that did the uh
the good good the good guide yeah so
that would have been something that
maybe they would have preferred to sell
to right large cooperative rather than
large companies
although there may have been problems
with scaling that the reason why i need
something bigger than that i
think it becomes an interesting
conversation when you're acquiring
companies
as a game b omni win because i think you
would sort of end up going to a company
and say hey
you're you have this value in a game a
world but
based on our charter we you know this is
our minimum wage
this is how much we pay people so if we
were to take your company
and turn it you know into our model it
would actually be making this amount a
year so we're only going to pay you x
like yeah so we would we'd we'd only be
winning
a sale of that if they had a
aligned moral compass or even if their
company was
profitable enough for us to be able to
make those changes right
which is sort of saying we'd only buy
companies that are actually
like sort of structured in a way to be
profitable
without underpaying people right like
if that's your business model yeah then
no we're not going to buy you right
the only thing is that in all of those
cases a gaming company will pay more
than we will
right so because they they pay on the
future potential
of the unlimited potential profit so
there has to be a reason why a person
would sell to us and like jubilee
i don't know that there's a lot of
people out there that wouldn't sell to
google because i think
a lot of the people that go into it are
trying to be jeff bezos
but there's also like it's not just that
they yeah some people would definitely
sell to google
like if they're going to sell we pay you
know 100 million and we're paid 100 000
clearly we know who you're going with
there's no reason to go with us
but when there's competition in that
area right if we're instead of building
our own food app buying one
google's not going to buy them because
they're they're like we're just going to
recreate you and we're kind of in the
same position but you already exist you
already have a customer base
that you can bring on board and if
you're you can see that your thing
like that someone will pay you 100 000
instead of you just going into the ether
and never
existing anymore that is the kind of
like we need a
food app we need a financial one a1 like
this and so to look at what's out there
and in the beginning yeah no one's gonna
sell to us because we don't necessarily
have enough money we don't have enough
but later on when um we are the option
cause it's like well if you sell the
google won't have money because why like
they're going to we will be acquiring
more things or a company that's
structured like this right that is owned
by humanity
would would have more power but not in
the beginning you could like in the
later stages you could end up with sort
of
uh like i don't know the human resources
version of economies of scale and just
like
being efficient where when google buys a
company in a lot of cases they just sort
of
leave that company alone and see if it
you know
can turn a profit as is and then see how
how how they can tie into their system
if the thing was hey a companies that we
acquire like well we might not need
the full-time marketing resources if
those marketing people get absorbed into
this marketing team that's company-wide
where they can be working on a bunch of
stuff you might end up
being able to be more profitable there
and i think what
realistically what you'd end up with is
most of the companies under the umbrella
are companies that were started under it
so it's sort of
if you have an idea you can either go to
the game a world and say hey i want to
put up my own you know
my my my own money or if i'm you know a
salesperson i'm going to try to get
investors and then i give up
a share of the company all that sort of
gaming stuff or we give them an option
well you can come here
where we take away pretty much all the
risk from that start
but then you also don't get the same
payout so
d do you want like a huge payout but a
huge amount of risk
or do you want a pretty decent payout
from a minimal
amount of risk and an organization you
know that you can feel good
being a part of
because yeah i think you were at the
hour so that's probably a good
enough place to stop
all right thanks for hanging out oh this
is our next oh next week we are doing
this at 2 p.m
five hours later than we normally start
it'll be our last time to get it if
it's just the five of us showing up so
if i'm gonna
post it tomorrow and i will tag the
three people i know who were
in that hemisphere and we will
see who shows up but last time i only
posted it like i think the thursday
before the saturday so this time
we'll give it a little more leeway and
see if people come
alright thank you youtube and facebook
see